thefastdiet.co.uk 2016-05-06

# Privacy and cookie policy - The Fast Diet

## Privacy policy

We guarantee our commitment to respecting and protecting your online privacy.

This includes your need and your right to know what we do with the personal information you share with us. It also guides our policies regarding the management of this data, including how the information is collected, processed, and for what purposes.

“The Fast Diet website”: refers to the web pages. By accessing this website you are consenting to the way information is collected and used, as described within this privacy  and cookie policy.

In return, The Fast Diet website gives the commitment that we will use the personal data you provide only in ways that are compatible with the following privacy policy.

We may disclose non-personally identifiable aggregated user data, such as aggregated gender, age, height, weight, and usage data gathered from our tracker (without the inclusion of a user’s name or other identifying information) on the website, available to the public, for purposes of comparison and inspiration. We may also disclose this data to other third party organisations, approved by us, for research and commercial purposes.

Every time you visit our website your IP (Internet Protocol) address registers on our servers. Your IP address reveals no information other than the number assigned to you. We do not use this technology to get any personal data against your knowledge or free will (i.e., automatically recording e-mail addresses of visitors). Nor do we use it for any purpose other than to help us monitor traffic on our website, or (in case of criminal activity or misuse of our information) to cooperate with law enforcement.

If you log in to access your account and / or make comments, we will register these visits with the information you provided when you registered and as given to us by the third party login providers as detailed in the registration process. We reserve the right to use this information to moderate comments and access to commenting if needed. We will never sell your data, you won’t get spam because you have registered with us.

We have implemented Google Analytics features based on Display Advertising  ([Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en)). You can [opt-out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the Ads Settings. In addition, you can use the [Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) to disable tracking by Google Analytics. We will use the data provided by Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting to develop the site and content around our users’ interests.

We use Akismet for comment moderation and to stop spam comments on our site. [Their privacy policy is here.](http://automattic.com/privacy/) We use the Stop Forum Spam service and SpamHaus to stop spam registrations. Here is the [Stop Forum Spam service privacy policy](https://www.stopforumspam.com/privacy) and [here is the SpamHaus privacy policy](https://www.spamhaus.org/organization/privacy/). 

If you have any questions about our privacy policy, please ask.

## Cookies

We use a number of different cookies on our site. If you do not know what cookies are, or how to control or delete them, then we recommend you visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) for detailed guidance.

The list below describe the cookies we use on this site and what we use them for. Currently we operate an ‘implied consent’ policy which means that we assume you are happy with this usage. If you are not happy, then you should either not use this site, or you should delete the cookies having visited the site, or you should browse the site using your browser’s anonymous usage setting (called “Incognito” in Chrome, “InPrivate” for Internet Explorer, “Private Browsing” in Firefox and Safari etc.)

## _First Party Cookies_

These are cookies that are set by this website directly.

**Google Analytics:** We use Google Analytics to collect information about visitor behaviour on our website. Google Analytics stores information about what pages you visit, how long you are on the site, how you got here and what you click on. This Analytics data is collected via a JavaScript tag in the pages of our site and is not tied to personally identifiable information.We therefore do not collect or store your personal information (e.g. your name or address) so this information cannot be used to identify who you are. We have turned on [Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en) to get an idea of our demographics and users’ interests. Please see above for how we use this data.

**WordPress:** Our websites runs the popular WordPress CMS and cookies are used to store basic data on your interactions with WordPress, and whether you have logged into WordPress. We use a **session cookie** to remember your log-in for you if you are a registered user and we deem these as being strictly necessary to the working of the website. If these are disabled then various functionality on the site will be broken.

More information on session cookies and what they are used for at <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/session-cookies-used-for.html>

## _Third Party Cookies_

These are cookies set on your machine by external websites whose services are used on this site. Cookies of this type are the sharing buttons across the site allow visitors to share content onto social networks. Cookies are currently set by **Twitter, Facebook, Google+, GitHub and Pinterest**. In order to implement these buttons, and connect them to the relevant social networks and external sites, there are scripts from domains outside of our website. You should be aware that these sites are likely to be collecting information about what you are doing all around the internet, including on this website. If you’d like information on how to disable companies tracking your web use, email us at [tech@thefastdiet.co.uk](mailto:tech@thefastdiet.co.uk).

Thank you to [Key Multimedia](http://www.keymultimedia.co.uk/privacy/) for allowing us to use their privacy and cookie policies as a template. If you have any questions about cookies on the site or our privacy policy, [please drop us a line](mailto:tech@thefastdiet.co.uk "mail The Fast Diet")!
